

# Noah Corbett

Boca Raton, FL 561.297.3340 ncorbett2014@fau.edu

Homepage in linkedin

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a fourth year doctoral candidate in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at Florida Atlantic University studying computational dynamical systems and differential equations. In my current research, I am developing methods that employ functional-analytic techniques and computer-assisted proofs to calculate connecting orbits in chaotic systems of ordinary differential equations and state-dependent delay differential equations, as well as travelling wave solutions of partial differential equations. In general, I view the computer as an invaluable tool in mathematics research and I enjoy learning and developing computational techniques to study open problems in mathematics.

### **EDUCATION** \_

#### **DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY.** Mathematics

Fall 2024 (Expected)

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

• 3.98/4.00 GPA

#### **MASTER OF SCIENCE, Mathematics**

2020

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

- MS Presentation: The Stable Manifold Theorem
- 4.00/4.00 GPA

# **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, Mathematics**

2018

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

- Minor in Statistics
- 3.84/4.00 GPA

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT**

2018-Current

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

• Duties include tutoring, grading, and teaching for undergraduate courses in mathematics and statistics

## **GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT**

2020-2021, 2022-2024

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

• Partially supported to perform data analysis on an NSF-funded project in collaboration with FAU's College of Education

#### NSF MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES GRADUATE RESEARCH INTERN

2023

U.S. ARMY CORPS OF ENGINEERS' RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER

Intensive summer-long applied mathematics research program, funded by the NSF and administered by ORISE

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

### As Course Instructor

- MAS 2103 Matrix Theory (Spring 2024)
- MAC 2312 Calculus with Analytic Geometry 2 (Fall 2023, Spring 2023)
- MAP 3305 Engineering Mathematics 1 (Fall 2022, Spring 2022)
- MAC 1105 College Algebra (Fall 2021)
- STA 2023 Introductory Statistics (Spring 2020)
- MAC 2233B Methods of Calculus (Fall 2019)

### AS TEACHING ASSISTANT/EMBEDDED TUTOR

- MAS 2103 Matrix Theory (Summer 2024)
- MAD 3400 Numerical Methods (Fall 2023)
- MAD 2104 Discrete Mathematics (Summer 2022)
- STA 3100 Computational Statistics (Spring 2021)

Publ	ICATIONS	
	"PREDICTING STATE SWITCHES IN CHAOTIC DYNAMICAL SYSTEMS"	Submitted July 2024
	WITH K. PILKIEWICZ AND M. MAYO	
[2]	"PERIODIC ORBITS FOR STATE-DEPENDENT DELAY DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS"	Submitted April 2024
	WITH V. NAUDOT	
[3]	"Stability of Travelling Waves: A Computer-Assisted Approach"	In preparation
	WITH J. D. MIRELES-JAMES	
[4]	"PERIODIC ORBITS IN THE STATE-DEPENDENT VAN DER POL SYSTEM"	In preparation
	WITH V. NAUDOT	
[5]	"RECRUITMENT AND RETENTION OF STEM TEACHERS IN HIGH NEED SCHOOLS:	In preparation
	AN ALUMNI SURVEY ANALYSIS OF SELECTED NSF ROBERT NOYCE PROGRAMS"	
	WITH D. KUMAR AND S. MOFFITT	
[6]	"A MIXED METHOD STUDY OF STEM TEACHER SUPPLY TO HIGH NEED SCHOOLS	In preparation
	IN FLORIDA AND TEXAS" WITH D. KUMAR, S. MOFFITT, AND C. RESTREPO-WIDNEY	
	ERS, PRESENTATIONS, & LECTURES RIODIC ORBITS FOR STATE-DEPENDENT DELAY DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS	
	RIODIC ORBITS FOR STATE-DEPENDENT DELAY DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS  APER PRESENTED AT:	
	024 Florida Women in Math Day, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.	April 21, 2024
<ul> <li>Special Session on Recent Developments in Nonlinear and Computational Dynamics,</li> <li>Spring 2024 AMS Eastern Sectional Meeting, Howard University, Washington, D.C.</li> </ul>		April 7, 2024
	Graduate Student Seminar, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.	March 29, 2024
	EDICTING STATE SWITCHES IN CHAOTIC DYNAMICAL SYSTEMS	
	PER PRESENTED AT:	November 17. 2023
	3 <sup>th</sup> Annual FAU Broward Research Symposium, Florida Atlantic University, Davie, FL. Graduate Student Seminar, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.	November 2, 2023
• Analysis & Applications Seminar, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.		October 19, 2023
<ul> <li>2023 NSF MSGI Summer Research Symposium (Virtual Event)</li> </ul>		August 22, 2023
• E	nvironmental Processes Branch Seminar, USACE ERDC, Vicksburg, MS.	August 10, 2023
THE STABLE MANIFOLD THEOREM		
	M.S. Presentation, Florida Atlantic University	April 17, 2020
	E DYNAMICS OF CIRCLE MAPS AND DENJOY'S THEOREM	- 1
	Multi-class lecture for graduate course in Dynamical Systems at Florida Atlantic University	February 2020
	<b>E FOURIER TRANSFORM, REGULARITY, AND SOBOLEV EMBEDDING</b> ecture for graduate course in Partial Differential Equations at Florida Atlantic University	November 2019
• L	ecture for graduate course in Partial Differential Equations at Florida Atlantic University	Novellibel 2019

# PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE \_\_\_

LANGUAGES: MATLAB | R | Python | LATEX

## FELLOWSHIPS & SCHOLARSHIPS \_

# ISAAC SCHUR GRADUATE SCHOLARSHIP

2021

 Awarded to graduate students in mathematics who have successfully passed two qualifying exams, maintained a high GPA in graduate studies, and received distinguished letters of recommendation from two professors

• Award of \$1,000

- Two-year fellowship awarded to doctoral students who have exhibited an excellent academic record and excellent letters of recommendation as determined by faculty at the time of admission
- Award of \$5,000 per year for the first two years of graduate studies

## FLORIDA BRIGHT FUTURES SCHOLARSHIP

2018-2019

• Undergraduate scholarship awarded to Florida public university attendees with distinguished GPAs and SAT scores

### **ACTIVITIES** \_

### **GRADUATE STUDENT SEMINAR, Organizer**

2022-Current

• Organized and co-hosted weekly seminars, with presentations by graduate students and faculty within FAU's Department of Mathematical Sciences

### **AMS STUDENT CHAPTER**

President

2023-Current

• Organized and lead chapter meetings, aided in organizing chapter events, and recruited officers and members for AMS student chapter.

Treasurer 2022-2023

· Managed funds and purchases for AMS-related events and activities at Florida Atlantic University

# FLORIDA ATLANTIC JAZZ ORCHESTRA, Lead Trombone

2016-2017, 2024-Current

 Attended biweekly rehearsals and performed at various venues for concerts and events as the first-chair trombone player

### **CERTIFICATES & HONORS**

- ACS Disaster Response Certificate (2024)
- CITI Responsible Conduct of Research Certificate (2023)
- CITI Social & Behavioral Research Investigators Certificate (2022)
- CRLA Level 3 Certified Tutor (2018)
- FAU Honors Program (2015-2018)